{"tossups": [{"question": "This author described traveling around London with a companion app programmed with W. G. Sebald's personality in an account of the Olympics for Grantland.com, \"Hard Times in the Uncanny Valley.\" In one of this author's novels, the protagonist intercedes for Ned the Copy Boy, a former office employee Xeroxing a picture of a butt forever. A \"sweeper\" nicknamed after Mark Spitz picks off \"skels\" in Manhattan in that novel by this author, which is set after the zombie apocalypse. This former television columnist for the Village Voice responded to a patronizing review by James Wood by parodying Wood's style in the essay \"Wow, Fiction Works!\" Lila Mae Watson searches for the \"black box\" in a novel by this author about warring elevator inspectors, and two slaves flee from Ridgeway on a literal train beneath the earth in his most recent book. For 10 points, name this contemporary novelist of Zone One, The Intuitionist, and The Underground Railroad.", "answer": "Colson Whitehead", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Colson <b><u>Whitehead</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Colson Whitehead", "Whitehead"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "At one of the Monday Evening Concerts in Los Angeles, Aldous Huxley got so carried away on the subject of this composer that he started fabricating titillating stories about him mid-lecture. Bernardo Bertolucci has continually shelved a film project about the life of this man that he first conceived in 1997. The structure of Bach's Musical Offering was taken as the model for a short story about performers of this composer's works, Julio Cortazar's \"Clone.\" In The Doors of Perception, Huxley recalls a mescaline episode in which he experienced the voices in this man's music as a \"bridge back to the human world,\" speculating about the \"psychological disintegration\" experienced by this Renaissance composer, calling him a \"fantastic character out of a Webster melodrama.\" For 10 points, name this Prince of Venosa who composed some revolutionary madrigals after committing a double murder of his wife and her lover.", "answer": "Carlo Gesualdo", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Carlo <b><u>Gesualdo</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Carlo Gesualdo", "Gesualdo"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Note to players: composer and type of piece required. The key of an unpublished seventh piece from a set of these pieces can be deduced from the pattern of expanding intervals in alternating directions exhibited by the first six, which have the tonics B- lat, C, A, D, G, and E. The last of those pieces in this genre by this composer includes two movements derived from an early version of the composer's sixth sonata for violin and harpsichord: a Corrente and a Tempo di Gavotta. Six of these pieces for keyboard make up the first of the composer's volumes titled Clavier-U\u0308bung (klah-VEEROO-bung). In one of these pieces in B minor,each of the four movements is paired with a Double (DOO-bluh), and a Tempo di Borea is substituted for the expected gigue. Another one of these pieces in D minor ends with an extensive and frequently excerpted chaconne (shah-KAWN). For 10 points, name these pieces, three of which for solo violin were paired with three sonatas, by the composer of The Well-Tempered Clavier.", "answer": "partitas by Johann Sebastian Bach [or Bach's partitas for keyboard; or Bach's partitas for solo violin; prompt on partitas; prompt on dance suites]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>partitas by Johann Sebastian Bach</u></b> [or <b><u>Bach's partitas for keyboard</u></b>; or <b><u>Bach's partitas for solo violin</u></b>; prompt on <u>partitas</u>; prompt on <u>dance suites</u>]", "acceptable": ["partitas by Johann Sebastian Bach", "partitas by Johann Sebastian Bach", "Bach's partitas for keyboard", "Bach's partitas for solo violin"], "promptable": ["partitas", "dance suites"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A mosaic in this city's Yaqto complex depicts a hunt scene surrounding an image of the pagan virtue Megalopsychia. Aurelian intervened to depose the heretical bishop Paul of Samosata in this city, whose Cherubim Gate opened to its Kerateion, a Jewish quarter. Because the Neoplatonist speaker Libanius taught in this city, Julian attempted to revive its Temple of Apollo by exhuming the corpse of Saint Babylas; Julian wrote the Misopogon because its citizens instead mocked his beard. In 253 A.D., Shapur I sacked this city, moving many of its citizens to a colony he gave a name meaning \"Better than\" this city. During a feud with the governor Gnaeus Piso, Germanicus died of illness in this city. Before becoming archbishop of Constantinople, John Chrysostom preached to Christians in this city. This city's Christians were the first to call themselves \"Christians.\" For 10 points, name this former capital of the Seleucid Empire on the Orontes in Roman Syria.", "answer": "Antioch [or Antakya; or Antiocheia]", "subcategory": "History Classical", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Antioch</u></b> [or <b><u>Antakya</u></b>; or <b><u>Antiocheia</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Antioch", "Antioch", "Antakya", "Antiocheia"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The most accurate computational model of these phenomena is the JONSWAP (\"john swap\") modification of the Pierson-Moskowitz spectrum. These phenomena are generated by the interaction of the Miles and Phillips mechanisms. A key parameter describing these phenomena is proportional to the one-third power of the cotangent of the revetment angle, according to Hudson's equation for rip-rap design. That parameter equals four times the square root of the zeroth moment of the variance spectrum of these phenomena, which are governed by Luke's variational principle. The Iribarren number characterizes instabilities in these phenomena that form below a value of about 0.07 for their H-to-lambda ratio. \"Rogue\" examples of these phenomena have over twice their \"significant height\" for a given set of marine weather conditions. For 10 points, name these phenomena that may travel thousands of miles before breaking on a beach.", "answer": "ocean waves [or sea waves; or water waves; or wind-generated waves; or rogue waves or swells; prompt on waves; prompt on surface waves; do not accept \"shallow water waves\" or \"tsunamis\" or \"tides\"]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>ocean waves</u></b> [or <b><u>sea waves</u></b>; or <b><u>water waves</u></b>; or <b><u>wind-generated waves</u></b>; or <b><u>rogue waves</u></b> or <b><u>swells</u></b>; prompt on <u>waves</u>; prompt on <u>surface waves</u>; do not accept \"shallow water waves\" or \"tsunamis\" or \"tides\"]", "acceptable": ["ocean waves", "ocean waves", "sea waves", "water waves", "wind-generated waves", "rogue waves", "swells"], "promptable": ["waves", "surface waves"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one paper, this philosopher muses that realism solves Nelson Goodman's new \"riddle of induction\" by positing \"perfectly natural\" properties that \"carve nature at the joints.\" In another paper, this philosopher argues that a \"rule of accommodation\" distinguishes conversations from baseball, in which walking to first base after three balls does not change the count to four. This author of \"New Work For a Theory of Universals\" and \"Scorekeeping in a Language Game\" characterized reality as \"a vast mosaic of local matters of particular fact.\" Applying the \"Ramsification\" procedure, this philosopher defended mind-body identity, a special case of his Humean supervenience (HYOO-mee-an \"super\"-VEEN-ee-ents). Statements like \"Had I made that shot, our team would have won the game\" are the subject of his Counterfactuals, which led him to propose the factual existence of infinite isolated universes. For 10 points, name this analytic philosopher who advanced \"modal realism\" in On the Plurality of Worlds.", "answer": "David Kellogg Lewis", "category": "Philosophy", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>David Kellogg Lewis</u></b>", "acceptable": ["David Kellogg Lewis", "David Kellogg Lewis"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A world in which all agents demonstrate the \"hyperbolic absolute\" version of this behavior was used by Stiglitz and Cass to derive the two fund separation theorem. It dominates above the horizontal axis of the inverse S-shaped probability-weighted curve, but not below the horizontal axis, in a phenomenon called the \"reflection effect.\" This behavior is measured by a coefficient equal to the negative second derivative of the utility function divided by the first derivative of the utility function, the Arrow-Pratt measure. Jensen's inequality can be used to prove that this behavior corresponds to a concave Von Neumann-Morgenstern utility function for an agent. Explanations for the Allais Paradox often invoke this behavior, as evidenced by the original \"Prospect Theory\" paper by Kahneman and Tversky. For 10 points, identify this microeconomic behavior exemplified in portfolio theory by a preference for safe, low-variance assets.", "answer": "risk aversion [or equivalents that convey propensity to take or not take risks]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>risk aversion</u></b> [or <b><u>equivalents that convey propensity to take</u></b> or <b><u>not take risks</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["risk aversion", "risk aversion", "equivalents that convey propensity to take", "not take risks"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This procedure requires a half-form correction in order to satisfy the Kostant-Souriau condition. This procedure cannot be applied to any Lie subalgebra of polynomials on the symplectic manifold R-two-n with order greater than two. In the Gupta-Bleuler formalism, this procedure includes the addition of a gauge-\u9001xing term to the Lagrangian to preserve Lorentz covariance. A form of this procedure uses the Kontsevich formula to de\u9001ne a star product algebra. Using the creation and annihilation operators to add and remove particles in Fock space is the \"second\" form of this procedure. The \"\u9001rst\" form of this procedure replaces the Poisson bracket with one over i h-bar times the commutator and replaces variables like momentum with their corresponding operators. For 10 points, name this procedure that converts classical \u9001eld theories with continuous variables to quantum \u9001eld theories with discrete operators.", "answer": "quantization [accept geometric quantization or quantization of the electromagnetic \u9001eld or deformation quantization or canonical quantization or second quantization or \u9001rst quantization]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>quantization</u></b> [accept <b><u>geometric quantization</u></b> or <b><u>quantization of the electromagnetic \u9001eld</u></b> or <b><u>deformation quantization</u></b> or <b><u>canonical quantization</u></b> or <b><u>second quantization</u></b> or <b><u>\u9001rst quantization</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["quantization", "quantization", "geometric quantization", "quantization of the electromagnetic \u9001eld", "deformation quantization", "canonical quantization", "second quantization", "\u9001rst quantization"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The FBS family of these constructs have their namesake property guaranteed via the well-known syndrome problem for linear codes. One of these constructs is a modi\u9001cation of the RadioGatun (\"radio\"-gah-toon) one and was made with a so-called \"sponge\" by Guido Bertoni and Gilles van Assche (zheel van ahsh); that one of these entities named Keccak was designed for a competition held by the National Institute of Standards and Technology. The version control system Git (giht) uses one of these constructs to generate practically unique identi\u9001ers for revisions. In Linux, the input to these constructs may be put inside a shadow \u9001le. These constructs are generally produced from one-way compression functions by the Merkle-Damgard construction. S\u00c2\u00b7H\u00c2\u00b7A-1 and M\u00c2\u00b7D\u00c2\u00b75 are examples of these constructs, which are generally used to secure passwords before they are stored in a database. For 10 points, name these constructs which map inputs to a number in constant time, whose values are o ten stored in namesake \"tables.\"", "answer": "cryptographic hash functions", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>cryptographic hash functions</u></b>", "acceptable": ["cryptographic hash functions", "cryptographic hash functions"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This tribe perpetrated the Williams Station Massacre in retaliation for the rape of two women by silver miners. This tribe's Chief Numaga caused the only historical disruptions to the Pony Express during the 1860 Pyramid Lake War. General Oliver Howard helped a \"princess\" from this tribe, Sarah Winnemucca, publicize the concentration camps that housed them after the Bannock War. This tribe denies allegations that some of its members helped John Lee's Mormon militia massacre the Baker-Fancher Party at Mountain Meadows. In 2016, Ammon Bundy's militiamen occupied this tribe's land in the Malheur National Wildlife Refuge. A shaman named Wodziwob from the Northern branch of this tribe, which inhabited California, Nevada, and Oregon, promised the return of the buffalo and disappearance of the white man. For 10 points, name these American Indians from the Great Basin who started the Ghost Dance movement.", "answer": "Paiute Indians [do not accept \"Ute\"]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Paiute</u></b> Indians [do not accept \"Ute\"]", "acceptable": ["Paiute Indians", "Paiute"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In one poem, this woman recalls her attraction to a stranger, saying, \"bullwhip, horsewhip, unzip, I could have crawled through thorn and bee, the thick of hive, rosehip, courtship, lordship, gossip and lavender.\" In another poem, she is called \"my more than meat and drink, my meal at every wink; this air, which, by life's law, my lung must draw and draw.\" This woman is the subject of a National Book Award-winning 2013 collection by Mary Szybist (SHEE-bist). Near the end of an epic poem, she is called a \"noonday torch\" and the source of warmth that enables the germination of a giant rose. In the Education, Henry Adams re lects that Americans were never afraid of either Venus or this woman, and contrasts her power with that of a device at the 1900 Paris Expo. The \u9001nal canto of Dante's Paradiso opens with a prayer to this woman. For 10 points, name this woman whom Catholics like Gerard Manley Hopkins call \"Immaculate.\"", "answer": "The Virgin Mary [or The Virgin Mary; or Mary, Mother of Jesus; or obvious equivalents; prompt on Mary]", "subcategory": "Other Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>The Virgin Mary</u></b> [or <b><u>The Virgin Mary</u></b>; or <b><u>Mary, Mother of Jesus</u></b>; or <b><u>obvious equivalents</u></b>; prompt on <u>Mary</u>]", "acceptable": ["The Virgin Mary", "Virgin Mary", "The Virgin Mary", "Mary, Mother of Jesus", "obvious equivalents"], "promptable": ["Mary"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Individuals possess \"contradictory\" forms of this construct according to a model designed by Erik Olin Wright. The \"X Way Out\" is championed as a way of superseding this construct in a guide whose \u9001nal section is a set of exercises with answers. That Paul Fussell book inspired a popular Michael Church blog post on this subject de\u9001ning \"E1s\" and \"L4s\" (\"e-ones\" and \"el-fours\"). 150 interviews with Boston residents on the psychological e\u9d01fects of this construct form the basis for Richard Sennett's book on its \"Hidden Injuries.\" It is constituted in the context of a \"\u9001eld\" by a \"habitus,\" a set of behaviors like appreciation for avant-garde art, according to Pierre Bourdieu's Distinction. Struggles de\u9001ned by this construct make up \"the history of all hitherto existing society\" according to the Communist Manifesto. For 10 points, identify this socioeconomic construct that, according to Marx, strati\u9001es people into the proletariat and the bourgeoisie.", "answer": "social class [prompt on answers like status or attainment, but class is necessary]", "category": "Social Science", "subcategory": "Social Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>social class</u></b> [prompt on answers like <u>status</u> or <u>attainment, but class is necessary</u>]", "acceptable": ["social class", "social class"], "promptable": ["status", "attainment, but class is necessary"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Anja Harteros (AHN-yah har-TAIR-ose) sang this role in an acclaimed recording conducted by Antonio Pappano that won the 2016 Gramophone Award for opera. One of this character's arias climaxes on a sustained high C marked dolce and pianissimo followed by senza aa\u0304frettare (SEN-zah ah-fret-TAH-ray) falling sixteenth-note thirds into the words \"non ti vedro, non ti vedro mai piu.\" A 1985 televised performance of this role at the Met marked the farewell to the stage of Leontyne Price, who also sang it in 1960, becoming the \u9001rst African American to sing a leading role at La Scala. In her last scene, this character sings the duet \"La fatal pietra\" with her lover, whom she wished would triumph in her aria \"Ritorna vincitor.\" This daughter of Amonasro sings the aria \"O patria mia,\" and is entombed alive with her Egyptian lover Radames. For 10 points, name this title character of a Giuseppe Verdi opera, an Ethiopian princess.", "answer": "Aida", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Aida</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Aida", "Aida"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "The Eckart conditions allow simpli\u9001cation of the ro\u00c2\u00b7vibrational Schrodinger equation that arises when applying this statement. A modi\u9001cation to this statement that better accounts for the electronic Hamiltonian is named for one of its formulators and Huang Kun. Potential energy surfaces can be calculated by applying the adiabatic theorem and this other statement. It allows the neglection of vibronic couplings. The Franck-Condon principle follows from this statement because it allows allows the separation of the initial and \u9001nal wave functions into vibrational and electronic components. For 10 points, name this approximation that assumes that the movement of nuclei and movement of electrons in a molecule can be separated, named for two scientists.", "answer": "Born-Oppenheimer approximation", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Born-Oppenheimer</u></b> approximation", "acceptable": ["Born-Oppenheimer approximation", "Born-Oppenheimer"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This essay's author claims, \"Few artists, not Goethe or Byron even, work quite cleanly, casting o\u9d01f all debris, and leaving us only what the heat of their imagination has wholly fused and transformed.\" In this essay, the author approvingly quotes William Blake's note \"The ages are all equal, but genius is always above its age,\" a ter urging the importance of \"the power of being deeply moved by the presence of beautiful objects\" over a \"correct abstract de\u9001nition of beauty.\" This essay argues that \"the \u9001rst step towards seeing one's object as it really is, is to know one's own impression as it really is, to discriminate it, to realize it distinctly.\" This manifesto of aesthetic criticism opens a book on an age \"productive in personalities, many-sided, centralized, complete,\" that also includes the essays \"The School of Giorgione,\" \"Sandro Botticelli\" and \"The Poetry of Michelangelo.\" For 10 points, name this short essay that introduces the magnum opus of Walter Pater.", "answer": "the preface to The Renaissance [prompt on The Renaissance]", "subcategory": "British Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>the preface to The Renaissance</u></b> [prompt on <u>The Renaissance</u>]", "acceptable": ["the preface to The Renaissance", "preface to The Renaissance"], "promptable": ["The Renaissance"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A poster from this country captioned \"Behold, the enemy!\" rendered a priest with a billowing cassock clawing both spires of a cathedral. A president of this country worked with Masonic temples to put soldiers under surveillance, assigning those who went to mass with cards marked \"Carthage\" and those who did not with \"Corinth.\" The Assumptionists published an anti-Semitic magazine called \"The Cross\" in this country. A reactionary movement coalesced here around \"integral nationalism.\" Reactionaries in this country reviled the A\u9d01fair of the Cards of Denunciation and erected a monument to Colonel Henry, a perjurious soldier. This country bulldozed over its religious establishment with a 1905 law passed under the Combes government. This country secularized its religious school system by banning Jesuits from teaching with the Ferry Laws, part of its drive towards \"laicity\" in the late 19th-century. For 10 points, name this country whose culture wars over the establishment of Catholicism intensi\u9001ed during the Dreyfus A\u9d01fair.", "answer": "France [or the French Republic; or Re\u0301publique franc\u0327aise]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>France</u></b> [or the <b><u>French Republic</u></b>; or <b><u>Re\u0301publique franc\u0327aise</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["France", "France", "French Republic", "Re\u0301publique franc\u0327aise"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A memoir relates how this writer checked himself into Silver Hill Hospital for psychiatric treatment in response to the disappointing reviews of the novel he believed to be his masterpiece. This writer's memoirs include an account of his father Herman's struggle with and eventual death from a supposedly benign brain tumor. This novelist had a strained relationship with his daughter-in-law Anna Steiger and disapproved of her long stays in his New York apartment. This author of Patrimony had his conduct as a husband attacked in the scandalous memoir Leaving a Doll's House, which was written by his actress ex-wife Claire Bloom, whom he portrayed in one of his novels as Eve Frame. Anatole Broyard's racial passing was long believed to be the inspiration for this writer's novel about Professor Coleman Silk. For 10 points, name this American writer whose alter ego Nathan Zuckerman narrates novels including I Married a Communist and The Human Stain.", "answer": "Philip Roth [or Philip Milton Roth]", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Philip <b><u>Roth</u></b> [or <b><u>Philip Milton Roth</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Philip Roth", "Roth", "Philip Milton Roth"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Once used to treat overactive bladders, mirabegron is now being tested for its ability to target this tissue's beta-3 adrenergic receptors. The exercise-induced protein irisin causes an increase in the number of these cells. Hibernomas are neoplasms of this tissue. A protein found in this tissue performs the same function as agents like 2,4-di-nitro-phenol. Unlike their counterparts which are uniocular, the cells of this tissue are multilocular. In adults, it is found predominantly along the clavicle and down the spinal column. The proton gradient of the mitochondria is dissipated by uncoupling protein one in this tissue. This tissue, which comprises 5% of the body weight of neonates and disappears with age, is the site of nonshivering thermogenesis. For 10 points, name this type of adipose tissue whose abundance of mitochondria leads to its dark color.", "answer": "brown adipose tissue [or brown fat, or BAT; prompt on adipose tissue; prompt on fat]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>brown adipose tissue</u></b> [or <b><u>brown fat,</u></b> or <b><u>BAT</u></b>; prompt on <u>adipose tissue</u>; prompt on <u>fat</u>]", "acceptable": ["brown adipose tissue", "brown adipose tissue", "brown fat,", "BAT"], "promptable": ["adipose tissue", "fat"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "A marble sculpture of one of these entities spies on Love binding two gods together in Paolo Veronese's Mars and Venus United by Love. Albrecht Altdorfer's \"Landscape with a Family\" of these creatures depicts a naked man assaulting a woman in a meadow in the background. One of these beings kneels over the stricken wife of Cephalus in Piero di Cosimo's Landscape with the Death of Procris. These creatures play with the helmet and lance of the sleeping Mars in Botticelli's Mars and Venus. In Bellini's Feast of the Gods, a bare-assed creature of this type carries a jar on its head; that creature of this type stands next to a drunk old man with a braying donkey, representing their companion, Silenus. For 10 points, name these Greek mythological creatures that represented lust in Renaissance art because they were half-human and half-goat.", "answer": "satyrs [or fauns]", "category": "Mythology", "subcategory": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>satyrs</u></b> [or <b><u>fauns</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["satyrs", "satyrs", "fauns"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "According to one story, this scholar was born with a blindness that was cured a ter Ibrahim appeared to his mother in a dream. He was exiled from his hometown for refusing to provide private lessons to the governor's children. The biographies of this man are \u9001lled with accounts of his prodigious memory, such as an incident in which he recited sixteen days worth of material a ter being chided for not taking notes. This man pioneered the use of categories like maudu and hasan. His technique di\u9d01fered from that of his greatest student Muslim ibn al-Hajjaj in that he required evidence that two people had met and not just evidence that they had lived at the same time. This man's masterpiece, which is divided into 93 chapters and sometimes called Al-Jami al-Sahih, was composed by selecting from 600,000 stories and sayings of Muhammad according to the trustworthiness of their \"isnads.\" For 10 points, name this Uzbek-born scholar whose namesake book is considered the most trustworthy collection of hadith.", "answer": "Abd Allah Muhammad ibn Ismail al-Bukhari", "category": "Religion", "subcategory": "Religion", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Abd Allah Muhammad ibn Ismail al-Bukhari</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Abd Allah Muhammad ibn Ismail al-Bukhari", "Abd Allah Muhammad ibn Ismail al-Bukhari"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Forces loyal to this man, commanded by his brother Nuri, broke through the Wolf's Gate to a city where they committed the September Days massacres. This general's attempt to encircle Russian forces without dependable communications led to disaster at the Battle of Sarikamish. This man reformed his country's military on the advice of Otto Liman von Sanders. Karl Radek persuaded this man to o\u9d01fer his services to the Soviet Union, but he instead died commanding the Army of Islam against Soviet forces in Turkmenistan in the Basmachi Uprising. This man delivered messages through \"Responsible Secretaries\" to a network of paramilitaries, Dr. Behaeddin Shakir's (beh-HYE-eh-deen shah-KEER's) \"Special Organization.\" This adherent of Pan-Turanism advised subordinates not to build settlements near the Baghdad Railway while marching deportees back and forth across the desert. For 10 points, name this military commander of the Young Turks' \"Three Pashas,\" the instigator of the Armenian Genocide.", "answer": "Ismail Enver Pasha", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Ismail Enver Pasha</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ismail Enver Pasha", "Ismail Enver Pasha"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}